SURYA BAHUBALENDRUNI

PROGRAMMER | DATA SCIENTIST | ENTREPRENEUR | STUDENT

CONTACT

Address

9322 Paragon Mills Lane Centerville, OH, 45458

Phone

(937)-266-5765

Email

surya.bahubalendruni@wustl.edu surya.b@winstongrand.com

Website

suryabahubalendruni.github.io

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/suryavb

ABOUT ME

Through my diverse and rigorous technical curriculum, I have built a unique skillset fit for any role I would find myself in at your firm. Moreover, I already have strong experience putting my knowledge to use outside the classroom. Indeed, I have started 2 successful businesses to date, giving me a professional maturity that would make me a strong asset for your company. Through my experiences, I have grown comfortable with handling ambiguous problems and working independently, making me a compelling candidate.

SKILLS

Apache SVN

Dreamweaver

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

• MySQL

Adobe

Jekyll

Languages Tools • Git

- Python
- Java
- C
- R
- SAS
- Assembly
- Arduino
- HTML
- CSS

EDUCATION

Washington University in St. Louis, Olin Business School Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (BSBA)

2014 - 2018

St. Louis, MO

- Majors: Economics & Strategy and Mathematics with a track in Probability/Statistics
- Minor: Computer Science (Note: On pace to finish all coursework for major, but listed officially as minor)
- Cumulative GPA: 3.6/4.0
- Business Coursework: Financial Accounting, Managerial Accounting, MicroGame Theory
- Mathematics Coursework: Calculus 3, Statistics, Matrix Algebra, Intro to Real Analysis, N-Space Calculus
- Computer Science Coursework: Intro to CS, Intro to Comp E, Discrete Math, Data Structures & Algorithms

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Winston Grand

Cofounder & Algorithm Developer

Oct. 2015 - Present

New York City, NY

- Started an algorithmic trading fund using Python as the primary tool for data science and strategy execution
- Designed a backtesting system that uses historical tick data in an event-driven architecture to properly simulate live trading and test strategies for various profitability and risk metrics
- · Built end-of-day strategies that use company fundamentals and earnings releases for signal generation
- Applied an assortment of machine learning techniques for effective strategy optimization
- Built an automated trade execution system with mature portfolio management and complex entry/exit technique

Villhard Growth Partners

Private Equity Analyst Intern

Jan. 2016 - Present

St. Louis, MO

- · Conducted due diligence research on potential investments in the tech-enabled healthcare services sector
- Compiled strategic recommendations consisting of industry analysis and company valuations on a weekly basis
- Discussed findings with private equity team to build a consensus on investment decisions moving forward

Washington University in St. Louis

CSE 132 Teaching Assistant & Webmaster

Jan. 2016 - Present St. Louis, MO

- Coordinated curriculum and graded assignments for 200+ students in an introductory computer engineering class
- Helped develop and manage content on the course's static website using HTML, CSS and Jekyll

KIPP St. Louis Consultant - Taylor Community Consulting Program

Sept. 2015 - Dec. 2015

St. Louis, MO

- Consulted alongside five peers for KIPP St. Louis, a K-8 non-profit charter school network that was looking to explore the feasibility of opening a new high school for children of low socioeconomic status
- Identified qualitative trends within our client's competitors by conducting administrator & student interviews, a SWOT analysis and a competitive landscape analysis
- Assessed key cost drivers and modeled short & long-term costs of a new school with national KIPP data
- Formed an opening plan and timeline to highlight our strategic recommendations for KIPP St. Louis
- Presented our findings to Enterprise executives, the Taylor Family, and the KIPP St. Louis Board of Directors

Next Step Tutoring

Cofounder & Mathematics Tutor

Jan. 2012 - Sept. 2014

Dayton, OH

- Cofounded a tutoring business that served 20+ students and netted profits exceeding \$10K
- Implemented curriculum to accessibly teach advanced fields such as Number Theory and Combinatorics
- Trained students for competitive math tournaments and standardized tests such as the ACT and SAT

ACTIVITIES

Phi Gamma Nu Professional Fraternity Recruitment Chair

Jan. 2015 - Present

St. Louis, MO

- Planned and executed marketing efforts and recruitment events for the Fall 2015 term
- Devised standardized method for best evaluating potential candidates for initiation into the chapter

Washington University Debate Team Collegiate Debater & Event Organizer

Sept. 2014 - Present

St. Louis, MO

- Competed in multiple forms of debate, including parliamentary debate (APDA) and various school events
- Oversaw public events and the Arch Invitational, a tournament attended by colleges across the country